- Okay, so now we're actually at the end of the course
but how do you get started?
- There are plenty of tool courses here in the library
but what do you do first?
When I first got into DevOps and infrastructures code
I came from more of a CIS admin background.
- Me too.
- Yeah, and one thing I did that really helped me
was to learn Ruby.
Chef, Puppet, Serverspec and Cucumber.
They're all written in Ruby.
And learning a new language
helped me to get up to speed faster.
- Maybe you come from a dev background
in which case you already understand the approach
but if you come from an operations background
you might consider taking some coding courses.
It doesn't matter what language
but Python can be helpful in the DevOps world.
Really just learning the process of development
will help you understand
how to perform infrastructure automation.
It's not just using the tools
it's following a development process.
- The culture change required to get yourself
and your colleagues to embrace this process is key.
Making changes through automation
and writing tests first for any infrastructure code
are basic techniques that you have to do all the time
every time to be successful.
- The other culture challenge is finding ways
to collaborate more tightly between the devs and ops.
Resist the urge towards local optimization
and choosing tools or processes
that are best just for you or your team
instead of what's best for the overall chain of teams
that have to work together to deliver the end product.
- But let's say you're willing to start.
How do you introduce this into an existing environment?
- One way to introduce new tools and techniques
is to choose an upcoming new project
and develop that project in the new way.
This is called a Greenfield Project.
- You know, our first pure implementation
of infrastructure automation
was in a Greenfield Project like this.
It's easier to get it done
when there's fewer legacy dependencies,
and then you can show the benefits to everyone else
in a real project.
- But sometimes you're stuck
with needing to change a legacy system.
What's charmingly referred to as Brownfield Development.
- And that brown isn't dirt.
- So true.
In this situation, look for a single process
to start with and automate it.
Ideally something that's a major pain point.
- When Ernest and I first worked together,
we inherited a large legacy web system
that had no automation.
We had to find a place to start.
So we identified the one piece to start with.
- We selected our Java application deployments
like I mentioned in an earlier video.
We chose a tool to use,
in this case was just a Perl script.
It was a long time ago.
So all these fancy tools didn't exist yet.
We defined the state we wanted to create using code,
tested it, and set up production monitoring
and unleashed it on the developers.
- We now know that was right
because that's what ChatGPT says to do.
- True story, bro.
- And then we used what was called
the strangler pattern to proceed.
We implemented a new piece of automation
for a piece of our stack, deprecate the old process,
and then eventually the new automated infrastructure
would strangle out all the old manual stuff.
- That worked well, but it wasn't as successful
as our second implementation when we realized
how important both test first
and integrating our infrastructure automation
with our continuous deployment pipeline was.
- Yeah, there's no single answer,
but we hope that this will give you some ideas
on how you can begin to incorporate
infrastructure automation into your own systems.
- We wish you the best of luck
in automating your own infrastructure.
We know that the benefits you'll see will change
how you work for the better.
Thanks for joining us.