- If you work in tech, you've probably either spent hours
building systems by hand
- Or waited weeks for someone else
to build those systems for you.
- Slow and unreliable.
What could be better?
- Well, today's systems demand a modern solution.
What you need is
- [Together] infrastructure as code.
- Howdy, I'm Ernest Mueller.
- And I'm James Wickett.
- We first met while implementing DevOps
at a large enterprise.
- And we've been friends ever since.
We both feel that infrastructure as code
is one of the fundamental practice areas of DevOps
and one of the most revolutionary.
- With IAC, as the kids call it,
you can generate high quality systems
that you can reliably test, consistently reproduce,
and change quickly and safely.
- Our course will teach you all the tools,
tips and techniques that we've learned over the years
to get infrastructure as code right.
- So let's start automating.