- Welcome back.
We've been talking a lot about the infrastructure itself,
but you may be wondering,
in the words of the great sainted Clara Peller,
"Where's the beef?"
Well, now we'll move on into the second phase
of explaining infrastructure as code
with infrastructure automation.
You can split automation frameworks
into two general camps, historically:
ones that configure the overall systems environment,
creating networks and servers and such;
and then, tools that configure
the operating system on the boxes.
Some tools do both,
but most have their roots firmly in one world
and just dabble in the other.
This is why we started
by going over cloud containers and serverless.
With traditional hardware,
you pretty much need to set it all up manually.
There are some tools to configure the boxes themselves
and the network a bit,
but the box and lines level of the system diagram
is slow and physical.
With these newer infrastructure technologies,
while they may have graphical interfaces
to click on to set things up manually,
they also have programmatic APIs
that can be exercised by tools or code
to build your network out on the fly.
This means we can use tools or code
to create our infrastructure from a defined description.
Each of the cloud providers has their own way to do this.
For example, AWS's CloudFormation
is a way to describe a complete network of systems
using JSON or YAML templates.
You then use a command line tool or an API
to feed that description into the cloud,
and it makes it for you.
Here's an example CloudFormation file
that describes creating a single EC2 virtual server,
with variables for the machine image,
instant size and such,
and some quick commands to update the OS
and start NGINX and boot.
You just feed it in, and, bam, about five minutes later,
you have a full running system in the cloud,
just like you went and clicked in the EC2 console,
but better because it's repeatable
and you can do it 100 times simultaneously if you want.
And you can build as large
and as complicated as system as you can model.
To update it,
you just change the model file and resubmit.
Now, you do have options
beyond the cloud provider-specific tooling.
There are similar tools
that try to provide a cloud agnostic solution.
Probably the most popular is HashiCorp's Terraform.
It has integration with most major cloud providers
and a large library of pre-existing modules
to make standard constructs like AWS EC2 instances.
And you can write your own.
You can buy it as a cloud service from them if you want,
but the tool itself is open-source.
Those tools are all declarative.
In other words, you write a description file
and the tool reads it
and creates the system that you've described.
There are also plenty of code libraries you can use
to build and manipulate cloud resources
in various programming languages.
AWS provides the CDK, or Cloud Development Kit,
which supports several languages.
A common solution here is Python's Boto library.
Here's an example of the code
to spin up an EC2 instance from within Python.
Here, you don't have a single description of the system.
You just add and change items
organically from within your code.
In case you were wondering,
yes, you can use these tools or similar ones
to create the base systems environment
for Kubernetes clusters and serverless architectures.
We'll talk about the up and downsides of these approaches
in our next video.