- There are many ways to create
your network infrastructure from code.
- But there's only one right one, Terraform.
- [Narrator] Everything versus Terraform.
Fight.
- Ah, come on Ernest.
We know that there's never one silver bullet in tech.
- Well, I'm not hunting werewolves,
until this weekend at least.
I'm building infrastructure
and Terraform's the way to do it.
It works across all the major cloud providers.
- But what about the cloud provider specific solutions?
Isn't AWS cloud formation optimized for AWS
and Microsoft Arm templates optimized for Azure
or at least they support all their new features?
- So, not really.
Besides those solutions being cloud provider specific,
they're made by different teams
inside those large organizations
and they lag their own feature releases too.
Since all cloud features are API driven
a third party module can get put together
as quickly as an in-house one in practice.
There's a huge Terraform community
contributing to the public Terraform registry.
So I'd venture to say Terraform support for each cloud
is as good as the cloud providers itself.
- Okay, well, but what about doing it
imperatively in code instead of using a tool
like Bodo or using AWS's own CDK?
- I don't know, man.
I've never been a big fan of that.
Not only do you need to rewrite a bunch of code
that an infrastructures code framework already has,
you're biting off a lot of complexity
and error prone fiddling.
Driving infrastructure from app code has its place.
For example, starting per user workstations
or something where you really need fine and instant control.
That's definitely not your core network.
You want your base infrastructure
to be well defined and repeatable.
- I've heard that you have to think about
how to store your infrastructure state in Terraform, though.
You don't want to just keep that on an operator's desktop.
- True. Well, cloud solutions
use their own API fabric as state storage.
In Terraform, you need to choose where to store your state
but it's easy to store it in any database
or an encrypted inversion controlled S3 bucket.
- But aren't you being all cloud-centric here?
What about on-prem hardware?
- So that's a fair point.
You can't easily do base infrastructure
using pure Terraform on bare metal.
There's some experimentation in that direction
but I personally would absolutely use something
like digital rebar that handles pixie booting instead.
- So, I gotcha.
- You would have if Rob Hirschfeld
and the smart folks at RackN
hadn't then made a digital rebar provisioner for Terraform.
Checkmate.
- Ah, snap.
Okay, I guess you're right.
It's a good thing that using Terraform at scale
doesn't result in a hell of core Terraform
and module version dependencies.
- Who told you that? Who told you that?
- You did.
- Okay. Well that that's true.
Complex infrastructures make for complex Terraform.
You need to compensate by breaking it up.
I've tried various packaging dependencies
and containerizing schemes.
Terraform can be too much for a simple job.
- I do see why you recommend Terraform.
You know, for so many cases it seems to have become
the most popular choice out there.
It has a lot of community and commercial support
but I have to admit, I still miss the provisioning framework
that we built together back in the day.
It built cloud infrastructure, but also did app deployment
and rationalized runtime service dependencies.
- Well, I agree, and the one drawback I find in Terraform
is the common flaw in all the available solutions, really.
There's a sharp separation
between infrastructure provisioning
and application deployment and runtime orchestration tools
largely based on historical ops team
versus dev team responsibilities.
And that's not very DevOps.
- Double snap.