- This course is designed to introduce you
to the basic concepts
of infrastructure as code DevOps style,
that means hot and sassy.
To get the most out of this course,
you may want to watch the course DevOps Fundamentals here
in the library for context.
In that course, James and I discussed
the foundations of DevOps
and how the three major practice areas,
infrastructure as code, continuous delivery,
and site reliability engineering fit into it.
This course drills down into infrastructure
as code specifically to discuss it in depth.
To get the most from this course,
you should be familiar with system admin basics,
be able to use the command line and SSH,
and be familiar with some sort of programming or scripting.
We'll be using the Linux Command Line on the AWS Cloud
and an Akaunting GitHub for our demos.
You should be able to reproduce it
from your desktop client of choice.
Our intent is for this course to be accessible
for anyone with even a basic IT experience.
While we're making our source files available to you,
this isn't meant to be a lab course where you follow along
and perform the activities to learn a specific technology.
Instead, we'll be talking
about infrastructure as code concepts,
why you would use them, and then illustrating
how to implement them in a variety of tools.
So don't expect detailed instructions
on how to install and configure those tools here,
but there are entire courses here in the library
on each one of them when you're ready.