- By now in the course,
you've seen how our ability
to use infrastructure as code is influenced
by the kind of systems we're automating, whether cloud
or virtual machines or containers or serverless.
- We've also walked through some examples using technologies
like Docker, AWS, Kubernetes, and Terraform.
But we really haven't addressed the implications
of infrastructure as code.
- What is this tangled web you weave, James?
- No, no, hear me out, Ernest.
Yes, we've seen our infrastructure in code
but there are a set of principles and practices that result
from treating our infrastructure as code.
- Okay, I'll allow it.
- In the next few videos,
we'll cover how treating infrastructure as code
means we can do all the things that we can do
for application code, but for our infrastructure.
- In the "Infrastructure as Code" book by Keif Morris,
he defines infrastructure as code
as an approach to infrastructure automation based
on practices from software development.
The emphasis is on consistent repeatable code
for provisioning and changing systems
and their configuration.
- So far, we've shown you how everything
in your infrastructure can be controlled by code
and represented in code.
But what does it mean to be treated as code?
- We have a saying in DevOps,
servers should be cattle, not pets.
You don't handcraft them and cater to their unique needs.
You mass produce them using a standard mechanism,
kill them and get more.
Leave the cool customizations for the back of your laptop.
- So infrastructure as code
is about adopting a development approach
to your infrastructure
and it's a cultural change more than a technical one.
- It's hard to wean yourself
from the tendency to log into the server and change it
but you'll have to.
Like fixing a code bug,
you'll change the code, build it, test it, and deploy it.
- When Ernest and I first worked together.
- At the dawn of computing.
- Yeah.
It was on a web team without any build automation.
Creating new systems was a 100-item manual checklist.
System changes and app deploys were done manually
during releases and documented in one
of those write-only change management systems
that, you know, enterprises love.
- So after a while, the configuration
of any given box was totally unreproducible.
Boxes that should have been identical weren't
and troubleshooting the many production issues
was a time consuming and difficult job.
- Some weeks of on-call rotation, I would get
like hundreds of alerts and pages
of all these problems in a really complex environment.
- Yeah, we lost at least one pager
from an on-call pager rage incident for sure.
- That wasn't me, you know,
but so later when we formed a new team
that we were building cloud-based SaaS products,
we agreed that our first priority
had to be the implementation
of a model-driven system that we would use to create
and operate our systems and applications.
Even though, you know,
we knew it was going to take more time to get going.
- We built a tool that would simply take models that devs
and ops collaborated on in source control, instantiate them
in the Amazon and Azure Clouds, deploy code
and dynamically hook up services to each other
in a pre-production environment first for testing naturally.
- The difference was amazing.
Suddenly operations became a nine to five job
and even our time at work was, you know, focused more
on design and implementation rather
than in firefighting and doing manual changes.
- In treating our infrastructure like it was code
was the secret sauce that made it work.
- Now, over the next few videos, we discuss how that works
in practice as we touch on version control, artifacts,
testing, using CI/CD and organizing our teams
around the patterns and principles that developers use.