- Testing is a programming basic
but many people still struggle with it.
Testing is even more critical than ever
as you increase automation
and the speed of change in your systems.
If there's only one thing that you take away
from this course,
it's that you should always test your infrastructure.
I'm an old school CIS admin,
and keeping production systems up and running
is job number one.
I understand a newfangled thing like continuous integration
and deployment might make you nervous,
but it's the single biggest breakthrough
in systems quality in decades.
Before this, the state-of-the-art was having a checklist
that you'd manually go down time after time
for each system you're changing.
If you're lucky, you'd run it on a test system
that may or may not be like production.
And as the kids nowadays say, "That ain't it."
Testing infrastructure is similar to testing code.
There's a concept called the testing pyramid
that describes a generally successful
and efficient approach to testing.
At the base of the pyramid is unit testing.
Unit testing is code level testing
and takes the smallest testable parts
or functions in your code and verifies their execution.
Formatters and linters also fall into this category.
You want to spend most of your time on unit tests.
They're fast and simple,
and they're your first line of defense
against simple errors.
In the previous chapter, we showed you some Terraform code.
Terraform has basic built-in tools,
like Terraform validate and Terraform format, dash, check
that ensure your Terraform is basically executable.
And there's a great open source tool called TFLint
that goes deeper into likely errors in your code.
Then you can write more specific unit tests
by using Terraform plan, which is a dry run
that shows what Terraform thinks it should do
from your description, but without needing to touch
any external infrastructure.
It generates a big load of JSON output
of Terraform's intended actions that you can parse
and look for things that you want to ensure in place.
Since these tests are quick and easy,
you can run a bunch of different scenarios
and configuration options
to make sure that your infrastructure code behaves correctly
for each combination.
The next level of testing is integration testing.
Integration testing is at the heart of infrastructure.
Sure, we can test the code that builds the systems,
however, the actual build and run time has to be validated.
Integration testing focuses
on testing several components together.
Integration testing takes more time and resources,
but it's obviously more effective
at validating actual operation than unit tests,
so you want to do it after the unit tests
will have already passed.
In Terraform, the way you do an integration test
is to Terraform apply your code in a test environment
and inspect the resulting system
to make sure it's configured all right.
Are the servers running?
Are the IP addresses correct, and so on?
And then you can just Terraform destroy it when you're done.
There are Terraform test frameworks like Terratest
and Kitchen-Terraform that can help you with this.
End-to-end testing goes a step farther
to validate the entire running system.
Infrastructure and application code testing merge here.
End-to-end tests exercise the APIs and UIs
of the resulting system
to make sure it's behaving in the way it should.
End-to-end testing is slow
and it has to have a fully constructed system
with applications and data and everything.
It also usually requires a lot of maintenance
and updating over time,
because your overall system changes a lot more often
than any single component does.
As a result, you want to keep the amount of these tests
to a bare minimum and test only the critical path.
But it's the absolutely best test,
because it emulates the actual user experience
instead of assuming
that the building's going to be solid
just because each brick is.
Then you can add in manual acceptance testing,
security testing, performance testing, and more.
I know that sounds like a lot,
but the beauty of it is it can be completely automated
in your build pipeline.
I ran a team at AT&T Cybersecurity that was responsible
for all of our cloud infrastructure,
for our SaaS security management product.
We had a Packer and Terraform pipeline
that ran out of an Atlassian Bamboo CI CD system.
On code check-in, it would run unit tests.
Then if those passed,
it would use it to build infrastructure
in a test environment and do integration tests.
And if that worked, it would run end-to-end tests
using Robot Framework and Selenium.
If those passed, it would queue it up
and prepare for a production deployment,
which would run out of our Rundeck orchestration tool
after any manual acceptance testing
the product team was doing for new features in that release.
We had performance and cross browser testing.
They were quite slow, so they ran on a schedule,
not on each code check-in.
I can't stress this enough.
If you're doing infrastructure as code without testing,
you're doing it wrong.
You can burn down a global system very quickly
through automation if not done safely.
As my Uncle Ben once told me,
"With great power comes great responsibility."
I miss you Uncle Ben!