- Okay. Sweet demo.
Are we done?
- No, it's time for a
- [Both] Bonus video!
(horn blares)
- Well, what else have we got?
What's newfangled and hot in the infrastructures code space?
- GitOps.
- Oh yeah.
The kids nowadays love their GitOps
with their iPads and their short pants.
GitOps is a way to do continuous delivery,
which aims to make the deployment process more reliable,
faster, and developer-friendly by using Git
as a single source of truth
for declarative infrastructure and applications.
- Absolutely, GitOps has been growing
in popularity as declarative orchestration frameworks
like Kubernetes have risen also in prominence.
- OpenGitOps is a set of open source standards,
best practices, and community-focused education
to help organizations adopt a structured approach
to implementing GitOps.
- Yeah, so let's review the definition
of GitOps as defined by OpenGitOps.
GitOps needs to exhibit these four characteristics.
Ernest, are you ready?
- Born ready?
First, it's declarative.
A system managed by GitOps must have its desired state
expressed declaratively.
- [James] Secondly, it's versioned and immutable.
Desired state is stored in a way that enforces immutability,
versioning, and retains a complete version history.
- [Ernest] Third, it's pulled automatically.
Software agents automatically pull the desired
state declarations from the source repo.
- [James] And lastly, continuously reconciled.
Software agents continuously observe actual system state
and attempt to apply the desired state.
- So what does this all mean?
Basically, you're skipping over a separate artifact layer
and you're just pulling a specific version of everything
out of Git revision control when you're deploying.
It does illustrate some of what we've already covered
in the course, and it can work really well
for driving declarative frameworks,
like Kubernetes, that are just waiting
for a new YAML configuration file to tell them
what all to load up.
- Right, and you know, GitOps is a great option
for treating infrastructure as code,
but we don't think that GitOps is the only way
to achieve infrastructure as code.
- No, that's right.
Because as great and well intentioned
as GitOps is, there are some drawbacks.
- [James] Yeah, right, for for one thing,
GitOps can be complex to set up and maintain,
especially if you have a large preexisting system
you want to transition to a GitOps flow.
- GitOps relies on storing the desired state
of the system in Git, which depends on the system
being able to interpret that fully and correctly.
You could see how there could be a desired state
that the system can't achieve.
For example, a new feature in a cloud service
hasn't been added to Terraform yet,
and it doesn't do any
of the dependency management things that Docker,
Nix or Wasm can give you.
- Yeah, and lastly, let's not forget
about visibility because, you know,
GitOps takes desired state and then applies changes.
You need a way to have real-time visibility
into the current state of the system
so you can troubleshoot problems.
- GitOps can be a powerful tool for managing the deployment
of applications to production environments,
but it isn't the only way to treat your infrastructure
as code.
I'd say you probably want to build most of your pieces
into artifacts and then only use GitOps to move out
the declarative recipes
of what you want running in production.
- Yeah, that makes sense to me.
And GitOps is also not the only way to fit version control
into your infrastructure as code implementation.
Hm, you can map artifacts to Git revisions
just using something like tagging.
- GitOps, it's all the rage
and it's good in some situations.
So just make sure that your infrastructure code
gets treated with the same care
as all the other code in your environment.