- In this chapter,
we're going to walk through a lab environment
built with a variety of infrastructure automation tools,
working together to create a complete working environment.
This lab is not an end-to-end walkthrough
of how to install and configure each of these tools
and how to write Terraform code, Ansible playbooks,
and so on.
There are entire courses here in the library
that'll walk you through setting up
and learning these tools.
Instead, our goal is to illustrate the concepts
we've talked about in the previous chapters
and let you see what infrastructure as code looks like
and how it works in practice.
Now, having said that,
if you want to try to follow along,
we have a detailed guide
on exactly how we set up our lab environment
included in the class materials.
You'll need a Mac or Linux desktop system
or a Windows system running Windows subsystem for Linux,
or WSL2, installed.
But all you really need to do from your local system
is generate an SSH key
and SSH into a cloud server you create.
You'll also need an Amazon Web Services account
with a credit card attached
as we'll be spinning up
a couple dollars an hour worth of infrastructure.
We're going to use an open source project called kubespray
available on GitHub
to create an AWS cloud infrastructure using Terraform.
Then we'll install Kubernetes on it using Ansible,
getting it ready for us to install our own application.
I'll walk through the infrastructure setup
and then James will walk through
the application deployment options.
And we're not just making a play infrastructure.
We'll be creating a redundant infrastructure
with appropriate network security in the cloud.
We'll take it step by step, though.
We'll do a separate video covering each layer.
Remember, the goal here isn't to become an expert
in AWS or Ansible.
It's to understand the ways you can automate
each layer of system set up
and prepare to take proper advantage
of infrastructure as code.
I'll see you back here to introduce you to the cloud,
in this case, Amazon Web Services.