- [Instructor] Welcome to "The Provisioning Lab."
If you already know how to use Amazon Web Services,
you can skip to the next video,
but I wanted to make sure that everyone's following along
when we make our infrastructure in Terraform
and go into AWS to inspect it.
Here, we're at the Amazon Web Services homepage,
aws.amazon.com.
If you haven't created an AWS account yet,
this orange button in the top right will offer you
a "Create a new AWS account" option.
In my case, my Alexa's been listening
to my every word and knows that I already have one,
so it just tells me to log onto the console.
That's just a little joke, Alexa. Please don't hurt me.
So now, we're in the AWS console.
Most things you can do in here you can also do
via the AWS Command Line Interface tool or the API,
but it's easier to illustrate visually here,
so we'll leave the CLI and API for later.
Remember, this lab isn't a full walkthrough of AWS,
but if you've just signed up
for an AWS account and you're logged in as the root account,
you're going to want to go into Security Credentials,
set up multifactor authentication on that account,
create a new IAM admin account,
I've made one called "emueller"
that I've given administrative rights,
and then log out as the root account,
log in as your new IM admin account,
set up multifactor authentication on that,
and then you can set
up the access keys that you're going to use
to programmatically access your account
over the course of the lab,
but using the root account
is the number one security risk in AWS.
You're going to want to lock that one away
in a box for a rainy day.
The number two security risk is not
having multifactor authentication set up on your accounts.
So, make sure and do those two things before we get started.
Here's the massive list of services available in AWS.
Everything from compute and storage and online databases,
to fancier things like machine learning services,
game development, all sorts of things,
but what we're going to go look at is under Compute.
EC2, which stands for Elastic Compute Cloud,
this is where you go to run virtual servers in the cloud.
So, there's only so easy
that Amazon can make running a server,
so you'll see here in the sidebar all sorts
of options for manipulating images, storage, networking,
security, and so on,
but you can get started with just saying defaults.
So, I'm going to show you how easy it is to start
a virtual server in the cloud.
First, go to this pop down in the top right
and pick a geographic region that you want
to run your server in
and switch to that region in the console.
I'm going to choose Oregon because I hear
that the data centers there
are outstanding in their field.
(Instructor snickering)
Okay, back to the console.
So, the Instances section is where you see
any servers that you have running.
We don't have any right now.
So, I'm going to go up to "Launch Instances,"
which is going to open up our little wizard
that they have for you to run a new server.
First thing, we're going to name it.
I'll just call it "Test Server."
Next, you pick an image to start it from.
There are all of the common operating systems represented,
thousands of community-contributed images,
and you can even create your own.
I'm going to pick Ubuntu 22.04.
Then, you pick an instance type.
This is essentially the hardware size
of the virtual server you're going to make.
This can be anything from a tiny micro instance on
through a bunch of larger options
and then all the way down to giant, bare-metal instances
with 48 CPUs and 384 gigs of memory.
This is running on my credit card,
so we're going to go for the small one.
So next, I'm going to pick an SSH key pair
to use to connect to the instance.
Now, I'm cheating a little bit
because you have to create this locally and then import it,
but instructions for that are in the lab materials.
Then, you set up any other options like network security.
I'm going to let us SSH
in from anywhere to make it easy to connect,
and then you have a bunch of other options,
how much storage, advanced details,
but I'm just going to take the defaults,
and then we go over here and we say "Launch Instance,"
and it says it has started to launch it.
You can see it's impending state.
When you click on it,
you can go in and see all sorts of other details,
especially the public IP address
that it's going to be available at.
Go check.
Sure enough, it made an eight-gigabyte disc for the storage.
You can look at your other security
and networking settings, and look,
it's already in running state.
That is super quick, and to prove it, let's connect to it.
I'm going to connect to it from the console.
We could do it via SSH, but this is quick and easy.
So, we'll connect in.
It's going to load up a virtual terminal here
in the web browser,
and here we are.
We are at the command line
of our very own brand new Ubuntu server.
That's faster than it'd take you to look
up Dell's phone number to order one.
Alright, so are you done with it?
Well, that's easy enough.
We'll go back here to the EC2 console,
and you can stop
and start the instance,
which is like powering it down and booting it back up again.
While it's powered down,
it's not incurring the charges
for the actual virtual server,
although there are still some charges
for keeping the disc alive,
but we're going to terminate it, completely destroy it.
So, it's going to warn us and say, hey,
whatever you have on that disc drive is going to go away,
and we say, that's fine.
It goes into shutting down mode,
and then, in less than a minute,
it will go in to terminate it and it'll be gone.
So, that's the cloud,
and that's how quickly you can get compute resources,
just as much as you need for just as long as you need it,
which is perfect for automation.
So next video, we're going to build some infrastructure
at scale with Terraform.