- [Instructor] Time for some fun using Terraform
for infrastructure provisioning.
First, let's look in our Amazon console.
Oh, look, under EC2, I've got a bunch of running servers
prepared to become part of a Kubernetes cluster.
So, you've got some running cloud servers.
"So what?" you ask. We did that in the previous lab.
Well, the spiffy thing here is that these are all generated
from infrastructure as code using Terraform.
Let's go look at that Terraform code.
I've forked an open-source project
called Cube Spray to do this,
and down in its contrib/terraform/aws directory,
it has the Terraform code
to make an entire Kubernetes cluster in Amazon.
So the first key item here is the terraform.tfvars file,
and this holds common configuration parameters
that you might want to tweak
in a normal Kubernetes installation.
Note here that we've got 3 workers running.
Then the primary Terraform code
is in create-infrastructure.tf.
As you can see, it details the parts of the infrastructure
to create the VPC, the load balancer,
starts getting into the servers.
Now, you'll note here that it's pulling in variables
from our tfvars file,
and then finally, we get to the piece
that creates our workers.
It also refers to specific modules
that hold more Terraform code.
So as you could see down here in the modules directory,
there are little submodules of Terraform
to do specific things.
This one creates the VPC,
and so it has all of the little bitty details
that are required to set up the networking in AWS.
This may seem daunting at first,
but there are a great many preexisting Terraform modules
out in the public Terraform registry,
including ones to perform basic building blocks like this.
Now, spinning all this up takes a little while,
so I've already run this Terraform.
Let's go back and see what it created again
in the AWS console.
As you can see, there's a set of servers,
a bastion, 3 master nodes, 3 worker nodes,
along with all of the associated networking
and security configuration.
Now, let's go to the system
that I downloaded this code to and ran it on.
There, you can see the code
that I showed you in the previous bit.
Now, the one difference here
is that since I've already run the Terraform,
it has something called a tfstate file.
The state file contains all of the details
of what it actually created.
So every single asset that it made,
it has all of the AWS details of what it did
and what it believes are running.
You can also store this state remotely
in databases or cloud storage.
You always want to do that for a production system,
but for this, I'm just saving it here in our code directory.
So, let's change something and run some Terraform.
Right now, we have 3 Kubernetes workers
that are all medium-sized instances,
as defined in our tfvars file, but I need more power,
so I'm going to add another server
to increase the cluster to 4 worker nodes.
So all we have to do is edit this tfvars file,
change the number of workers to 4,
and we're going to save it.
Now, the first thing that we're going to do
is run terraform validate.
That is going to look at the code
and make sure it all looks well formed
and we didn't make any terrible mistakes.
It tells us the configuration is valid.
So then we're going to run terraform plan.
Terraform plan goes out and actually dry runs this code
and comes back and tells you
exactly what it thinks it's going to change.
So here,
you can see that the previous servers,
it's not going to touch.
It's going to create a new server, Kubernetes worker 3,
and then it's going to change the inventory file
that it uses to keep track of things.
So this is how you verify
that it's going to make the change you want,
and it's not going to go affect anything
that you don't want it to.
So all we have to do is run terraform apply,
so, prepares to make the change,
then it's going to show me the plan again
and ask me if I am sure, and I say yes.
And away it goes.
Back over here in the AWS console,
you can see that worker 3 has already started
and is initializing,
so we have a newly larger Kubernetes cluster.
Now, back at the command line,
let's run terraform plan again.
It says our infrastructure matches the configuration,
so our specification and reality line up.
So let's check in the tfstate file.
Sure enough, there is worker number 3,
with all of the details about
how it got set up inside of AWS.
And that's the real power of infrastructure as code.
You can spec out exactly what you want,
have others review it, run it in a development environment,
and then run it in your production environment
with no room for manual error,
both to create your infrastructure in the first place,
but then also to precisely change it over time.