- [Instructor] We've provisioned some infrastructure,
but what about configuration management for the software?
We made servers, but Kubernetes isn't just automatically
running on them.
So now we're going to use the other part of kube spray,
the Ansible playbooks, that actually install Kubernetes.
Let's take a look at one of the simplest playbooks included,
the one that checks the Ansible version.
As you can see this playbook, it checks the Ansible version.
It does a couple other things
like checking the Python and Jinja versions to make sure
that, you know, it can run on this system.
So let's run it.
We run it with the Ansible Playbook command
and we just feed it the playbook.
So it takes it, it runs it,
and it performs all those commands.
And as you can see here, it's checked the Ansible
and Python and Jinja versions, and they all pass.
So, it's good.
Now let's look at the main playbook, cluster dot yml.
You can see at the top, the first thing that does
is include that Ansible version playbook that we just ran.
Then it goes on to set up the different kinds of hosts
in our system.
And as you can see,
the primary thing that it does is apply roles to them.
Each role, in turn, is defined by one or more playbooks.
Let's go take a look at the Bootstrap OS role
that it's putting on most of these servers.
So here, down in the tasks directory,
is where most of the code actually is.
Let's take a look at the Bootstrap Debian file
because we've been setting up
Debian servers for our Kubernetes.
All right, so in here it goes through all
of the little things that it does to get each server ready
and you know it's low level stuff,
installing Python, adding other packages to it,
doing a apt get update.
At the bottom level,
there are either commands that Ansible knows how to perform,
like package here is a Ansible keyword that says, okay,
I know how to install a package on this operating system.
Go ahead and do it.
And then there are ones called raw
which in the end says, execute this command line, right?
So for something that doesn't fit neatly
into one of the existing keywords,
you just say raw and say what you want it to do.
All right, so let's talk
about running Ansible on remote servers.
So first, let's look
at the inventory file that our Terraform made.
If you'll recall, when we ran the Terraform, each time
it would output this inventory file that has the host names
and IP addresses of all the components.
This is so that Ansible can go
and find them to do what it needs to do.
They're broken up into roles
so that it understands which, you know,
which servers have the control plane running
on them versus being workers.
It should come as no big surprise
to you by now that I'm a big old cheater.
So I already ran cluster dot yml to install Kubernetes
across all the servers.
It takes a gruesomely long time.
So let's run kubectl, get nodes, and it shows
that we've got three control plane nodes already set up
with Kubernetes and three worker nodes.
But you may have noticed that in the last lab
we used Terraform to add a fourth worker
and we see it listed in the inventory file.
Right?
We've got four kube nodes here
but we don't see it in Kubernetes.
Well, that's because we haven't actually
installed the Kubernetes software on it.
So let's use a playbook that they use specifically
for scaling up a cluster.
It's called scale dot yml.
So it's like cluster dot yml,
but it doesn't have to do all the core cluster work.
So goes through, installs some things.
Notice how it's having to do a couple different iterations
on the servers to get it working.
So it has to go install some prerequisites,
then go install another batch of things,
and install a third batch of things.
And then at the end,
we should have working Kubernetes on that remaining system.
So let's check out this Ansible command line
that we're going to use.
So first we're saying use the inventory hosts file to figure
out where all the servers are, use the scale dot yml
playbook and then we have a number of parameters
around how to connect to the other system.
So, let's run this command
and have Ansible automatically go determine that one
of the listed server nodes does not have the software on it
and then install all the Kubernetes goodies.
So this is going to take about 15 minutes end to end.
So I'm going to press the turbo button on my computer
to skip to the end.
Alright, finally, we're back
after 13 minutes and 35 seconds of installing.
Now that seems like a long time,
but we installed literally hundreds of software packages,
docker containers, and configuration items.
So let's take a look at Kubernetes.
And there is our fourth worker node ready to go.
And all of the default control plane
and cubelets and all of that are set up and running
and this Kubernetes cluster is ready to use.
So, that's Ansible.
You construct nested playbooks to build up all the software
you need, and then you can execute them
either locally or on remote machines.
You can even orchestrate complex workflows,
like cube spray includes an upgrade cluster playbook
that can perform graceful software upgrades on your cluster
by coordinating and draining individual nodes
and then doing an installation in a rolling manner,
to do it without any application disruption.
By automating and testing your operations in this manner,
you can perform identical operations across large numbers
of servers with a high degree of safety.