- [Instructor] Now that James has told you
about Docker containers let's get an application
deployed onto our Kubernetes cluster.
It's sitting here empty except for all the default services.
Very lonely.
So we could do this by hand, but we're not animals, right?
This is an infrastructure as code course.
So we're going to use IAC to deploy our applications as well.
In the cloud native ecosystem, Helm charts
are a popular way of deploying applications.
This is the Helm homepage, helm.sh.
Here you will find a lot of documentation
and resources to help you along your Helm journey.
I've already installed Helm on this server,
but the instructions to do that are in the course materials.
Now, there are a lot of Helm repositories out there
with ready to use charts already.
Here. I've added the Bitnami repository to our local.
And then we can search this repository
to see what all it has in it that we can use.
And as you can see, there are a lot of Helm charts
in here for open source projects.
Everything from Airflow and Apache,
down to WordPress and Zookeeper.
So let's download one and take a look at it.
Let's say the Nginx web server.
We can do that with helm pull,
and then the name of the Helm chart.
All right, so it downloads it as a TAR zipped file,
so we will unpack it.
So now if we go into our Helm chart directory
you could see a number of files.
So the values.yaml is very similar
to the terraform.tfvars file in that this
has a bunch of top-level settings to describe
how you want to configure your Nginx server.
It has a whole bunch of them because even a simple thing
like a web server, you can set a lot of different things.
Then inside the templates,
here you have a file for each kind of Kubernetes
component that has to be generated to deploy Nginx.
So it has here the configuration to make a deployment
and to make a service and to make a ingress controller,
all that good sort of thing.
So let's look at deployment.yaml.
All right, as you can see this,
it looks like a normal Kubernetes deployment
but it's full of all sorts of both including variables
and doing conditional logic on variables.
But you're probably feeling froggy by this point.
Who wants to deploy something pre-existing again?
So let's forget Nginx,
and let's make our own Helm chart.
And we'll use it to deploy James'
word cloud generator application.
So Helm can create a stub chart for us.
Let's ask it to create one called wordcloud.
All right, we go into the wordcloud Helm chart directory
and it looks like a stripped down version
of the Nginx one, which is actually exactly what it is.
So doesn't have all the bells and whistles
but it's essentially just deploying a Nginx web server
with all the components required to do that.
So let's change this to do what we want it to do.
So instead of installing Nginx, we're going to change
that to get James' word cloud generator.
And let's see, let's go ahead and change
the replica count to three so that we can have
three of these running instead of just one.
And then to make sure that we can expose it to the internet
we're going to go down here to the service
and we're going to change it to a load balancer.
And you may recall that James'
container listened on port 8888.
So that's what we'll go ahead and set.
And then you know how James
mentioned the different architectures?
So he uploaded a couple different versions
of this word cloud generator.
And so we're going to pull the tag for latest-amd64 so that
we make sure and get the AMD architecture version of it.
All right, we're done with that.
So first we're going to ask Helm to check our syntax,
make sure we didn't mess anything up.
My typing isn't what it used to be.
And it says it's fine.
It recommends us setting an icon somewhere
but we can ignore that.
And now we're going to essentially dry run this, have Helm
exercise it and see what it thinks it's going to do.
So for that we're going to use
helm template --validate --debug wordcloud.
So it's going to parse the Helm chart and say
these are the different things that I'm planning
on creating based on what you said.
You know, this deployment,
this pod.
And it all looks pretty good to me.
So we're going to tell Helm to go ahead and do this.
So with that, we use helm install.
We're going to call our application wordcloud.
We want it to pull the Helm chart from our little
wordcloud directory that we have here.
and we're going to specify the file to get the values
from which is of course, inward cloud, it's our values.yaml.
Then we run that.
And so it's going and installing the Helm chart
on our Kubernetes cluster and then creating
all of those different assets.
So now if we do a helm list,
it says hey I have an application called wordcloud
that the revision 1 has been deployed.
So let's take a look.
All right, we have three running pods.
We have a load balancer.
And we have a deployment and a replica set.
So that seems good.
Let's check it out.
So this is the name of the Amazon
Elastic Load Balancer that it created.
This should be accessible from the internet.
So first, let's quick check it from local.
We're going to curl just the headers.
And don't forget, we need the port 8888.
Ah, and we're getting a response.
That's nice.
So now let's get fancy and try running this in a browser.
All right, so I'm using Google Chrome.
We're going to put in that ELB address with port 8888.
And it looks like we've got his word cloud app.
A word cloud.
Outstanding.
And there we go.
A working application live on the internet
set up with resilience in a Kubernetes cluster.
And we built each layer using infrastructure as code.
One parting note, you've seen how much the community
is already created out there in GitHub,
Docker Hub, the Terraform Registry of Modules,
Helm repositories, all great learning resources.
Don't just copy and use things blindly,
but don't be afraid of reusing and eventually contributing
to these high quality community assets.