- In this video, we'll talk about the pipeline you'll set up
for your systems to take them
from code to artifacts to running system.
Here's an illustration of a continuous delivery flow
where code gets checked in, built,
goes through successive levels of testing
and finally gets released to your production environment.
But why do you want to do this?
Well, this process does a couple of things.
First of all, it isolates changes.
If you check in small batches of changes
and build and test each one,
you know when something goes wrong.
It also lets you trace back a specific deployment
to a specific build, to a specific code change as opposed
to having to make any changes in the environment by hand.
The day of live code changes
on production servers is mostly over
and so it should be with infrastructure.
So how do you do this?
First, you'll want to use source control.
If you're not experienced with it, it's easy.
We'll use Git in this course, and there's courses
in the library to show you the basics of Git.
Every time you check in code, a trigger fires
and the build system goes to test
and build and test it some more.
Like application code,
you'll want to have tests for your infrastructure code
and the actual running infrastructure.
It's such an important topic itself
that we'll cover it in depth in the next video.
And then the build.
Code usually gets compiled, parsed
or even bundled up into what we call artifacts.
Artifacts are versioned, unchanging sets of code
that get tested and deployed.
For infrastructure artifacts,
you usually see ZIP files, Debs, RPMs,
Docker images, AMIs, or VMs.
There are some very cool new options
worth checking out though,
like the Nix package manager that's designed
to let you make declarative reproducible packages
and web assembly or WASim, a format
for a stack-based virtual machine
that's a portable compilation target
for all kinds of languages.
One of the co-founders of Docker says
they wouldn't have needed to create Docker
if WASim had existed back then.
There's no single right answer.
They all have advantages or are necessary
for different scenarios,
but deciding what your artifacts are
and how to manage and version them is very important.
Here's a reference architecture
of a DevOps service delivery platform
showing the flow from source repo to build
and then to artifact repo, and then out into production.
You may have multiple layers of artifacts, and that's okay.
For example, one team might build everything
into OS packages for their Java and Python applications
and leverage built-in dependency management.
Then as a second layer, they might build VM images
and AMIs using Packer and build Docker images directly
with Dockerfiles containing applications deployed
from that first tier of artifacts.
And this is usually controlled
through a build system like Jenkins or Bamboo
or something similar.
To store artifacts,
it's common to use Artifactory
or Nexus or a container registry
but I've seen it all with some people just keeping it simple
and using a cloud storage bucket.
The last step is deployment.
Here's an example of that previous artifact flow
with a specific tooling that Ernest used over at AlienVault
for their continuous integration pipeline.
AppCode and Java
and Bash, infrastructure code and CloudFormation
and Puppet all checked in to Bitbucket source control,
and using Maven and the Bamboo CI product.
Artifacts such as AMIs,
VMware images and Debian packages go into Artifactory.
And then a continuous deployment job
in Bamboo runs the Rundeck orchestration system
to deploy production via Puppet and Terraform.
All together, that formed a comprehensive app
and infrastructure service delivery solution.
And that's the basics
of continuous integration for infrastructure as code.