- Hey, Ernest, your newest code change
ended up crashing Docker in production.
- Well, it worked on my machine.
- Ah, you say that like that's a legitimate excuse.
It's all right.
You know, believe it or not, deployment is a necessary step
in your work, bringing actual value to users.
- It's the D in CI/CD.
- And in an infrastructures code world, it's code two
and it needs testing.
- What you really want is reproducible infrastructure
that works across all your environments
with repeatable results from dev to test to production.
This assures you that behavior will be the same
as you expect during your development.
- Yeah, that's right.
If you can have repeatable deployments
then you can do rollbacks, you can do roll forwards
with your infrastructure and not just your application code.
Because as much as we like to think they're independent,
they're not.
- And then you can reproduce environments
for troubleshooting and experimentation.
- Okay, but how do you do it?
Environmental differences have always been
a sad fact of life for decades.
Everyone knows that they're supposed to have identical tests
in production environments
but usually they're just somewhat similar at best
which leaves room for new bugs to show up.
- Three steps, step one, versioned artifacts for your code
and your infrastructure code.
- And step two, use that code to make
a production-like environment
in each phase of the dev cycle.
- And step three, have a mechanism to deploy it
in an identical manner in each of those environments.
- Okay, let's talk about artifacts.
This just means you package up and version your code
like every library that's out there.
- It can be an actual bundle
like an RPM or Debian package, or even just a GIT revision.
But the key thing is it can't ever change.
It needs to be constant once generated
and then used in each environment.
James talked to you about artifact generation
just a couple videos ago.
- Ah, you remembered.
- Oh, I wouldn't forget it, bro.
- Ah, thanks.
Well, next identical environments.
If you're generating your environments
from this disc code, most sources of difference
are from people making compromises.
- While you often do have to compromise on scale
a lot of the schemes I see to try to save money
on dev and test environments
end up being penny wise and pound foolish.
Yes, it can be more expensive to spin up servers
in the same cloud providers, your production environment,
you might need to buy that Oracle license
or pay for that Datadog monitoring,
but the fact that you're paying for that stuff
in the first place means the business thinks
your app is worth it.
So behaving in a way that's guaranteed to make it slower,
riskier and buggier to change that app,
usually not a great idea.
- Yeah, of course, being perfectly identical can be hard.
You know, scale and traffic differs at least
but your code shouldn't.
Externalize things like URLs to configuration
so you can configure your different environments
in a way where they should at least behave the same.
Even the developer's desktop can get close.
There's a lot of tools like Vagrant, Docker,
Compose and Minikube that improve alignment
even before you hit an external environment.
- And finally, the deployment.
Deployment is code just like all the rest of this.
So however you deploy your app in production
is how it should be deployed in pre-production.
This will prove to you both that your deployment code works
and that the application and infrastructure components
behave correctly when deployed.
If you have stable versioned artifacts,
generate your own identical environments
and deploy with the same code in each place,
you've gotten to a pretty darn good situation.
- Yeah, well, you know, back when Ernest and I
were working at National Instruments,
we did a lot of manual deployments of Java apps
across a cluster of app servers.
It was slow and it relied on manual instructions
from developers.
A lot of the time the instructions weren't right
and even if they were then we'd sometimes make a mistake
on one of the servers.
We wrote a simple deployment script that they had to use
in the dev and test environments
before we used it in production.
And suddenly speed of deployment shot up
and post-deployment bugs shot down.
- And that let us get to step four, profit.
- Profit?
- Well, or at least we had to do less off hours work.
- Okay, I'll call that profit.