- Now that we're doing our infrastructure as code,
this ends up having more implications on how we work.
- That's right.
You're now developing both your app code
and your infrastructure code
and testing and deploying it identically.
- But what does that imply
about how we support it in production?
- This may not be a surprise
if you've taken our DevOps foundations course
or it's follow up DevOps Foundation
site Reliability Engineering.
But it's a shared responsibility.
- Yeah. We always think our code is going to work right
in production, whether that's app code
or infrastructure code, but even
if it does upfront things change.
You get more users.
They start using your app in different ways.
- Someone needs to handle the problems
and figure out what's going wrong.
And the best person for that job is you.
- Yeah. As the person who wrote the code
you're the one most able to support it and change it.
Throwing it over the wall
to someone else tends to make both someone less familiar
with the code figure out the problems
which they're naturally less positioned to do
and it hides the problems from you,
the person who can actually fix the problems at their core.
- Avoid passing the responsibility to someone else.
By handling your own production environment,
you're making the most effective feedback loop possible
from problem to fix.
Note that Google's SRE model
for taking all over our operations from a product team,
it's only used for apps with very large user
bases that have proven themselves stable
and have monitoring and tools in place sufficient
for the SRE team to agree to take it on.
Short of that, it's best practice to run it if you wrote it.
- So how do you do that?
Well, first you want to take a team approach
with however many other teams are contributing code
to that environment.
- [Host] Put together good observability
to monitor the system
and discern what's going wrong.
- [Host 2] Have a practiced incident management process
that makes handling problems routine and less stressful.
- When there's a problem
prioritize coding and testing a real fix.
Don't just keep putting out the fires each time they happen.
I mentioned that AT&T Cybersecurity SaaS product
that I worked on.
We had a complete CICD pipeline.
They rolled out infrastructure code and app code.
We had loads of monitoring
and could route issues to the right team pretty reliably.
- Now, what did you do for problems where it wasn't clear
what was wrong?
- In most places I'd worked up until then
operations was always the first line
of response for production issues.
But in this case, the majority
of them were being caused by our app code.
So we put the developers on call first and let them escalate
to an operations engineer if they needed one.
That reduced overall off hours time spent,
and it meant that very actionable improvements could get put
into the product backlog.
- But didn't your product people object to that work
interrupting their precious future development time?
- Not at all.
The product people wanted the product to work right
as much as anyone and were happy for us
to prioritize reliability work,
especially when we had such direct data
to prove the results it would have generated
by people knowledgeable with the code.
We called it eating our own dog food.
- Ah, some people like to say, drinking your own champagne.
- That's 1% or nonsense.
I work for a living.
- Okay, Ernest.
All right.
All right. Look, there, there.
Let's get you a nice nap and then we'll be back for a video
on running the rest of your operations as code two.