- Okay, so we're done now.
Our infrastructure is code,
and so thank you for joining us in this course.
- Well, hold on, so it depends what you mean.
There's your applications and your infrastructure,
but people may be forgetting about some other pieces.
What about your monitoring,
your runbooks, your documentation,
your API definitions, your SaaS integrations?
- Well, you know, I thought I'd just, you know,
click around and set all that stuff up manually.
- Have you learned nothing?
- Well, you know, seriously,
now that you have big parts of your system as code,
look to see what else you can codify.
- All these things are part of your system,
and they're all in scope
in terms of reliability, performance, and security.
- The application boundary isn't just the code anymore.
All the benefits you get out of infrastructure as code,
the testability and repeatability,
you want all that in all the other pieces of your system.
- The great thing is infrastructure as code
has been made possible by the rise of APIs,
so you can program to them to create your infrastructure.
Well, the majority of your SaaS providers
and tools also have APIs nowadays.
- [James] Yeah, for example,
instead of setting up monitoring dashboards by hand,
you can define them in code
and then load them into tools, like Grafana or DataDog.
- [Ernest] Same with your support runbooks.
Version them and then deploy them from an artifact.
- There's plenty of tooling nowadays
to help you generate documentation from your code
as well as information
on what can be monitored or manipulated.
Yeah, these are all, at their heart, version code as well.
- Then apply all the same principles we've talked
about here to them.
Deploy your monitoring setup via API
in your pre-production environments
as well as your production environments.
This makes sure your monitoring runbooks
and so on are always linked
to the right version of the apps
and infrastructure they were designed for,
and it lets you test them as well.
- Yeah, I wish I could say
I've never seen monitoring cause a production outage,
but I have.
- That's right.
The pattern of define, build, test, deploy is
a best practice for anything you can apply it to.
Challenge yourself when you're doing manual work.
Is there a way to do this as code instead?
- Many of the tools
in this space have started building ways
to express these extra components as code.
Take Terraform, for example,
we have a big library of providers
that let you manage, you know, Salesforce users,
DataDog dashboards, Splunk logging,
even passwords in 1Password, CDNs, DNS, and much more.
- I had a team that wrote Bash shell scripts
using the Rerun framework and built them into artifacts
for the Rundeck Runbook automation system to use.
We then used those scripts in Rundeck
to orchestrate all our production operations,
and changes to them were coded,
versioned, tested, deployed in test,
and then used in production
in a controlled and auditable manner.
- Ah, you know, it's a big difference
from back in the day when it was controversial
for CIS Admins to even use source control.
- We've come a long way, baby.