- [Instructor] In the video on Docker,
we published a Docker image to Docker Hub
that Ernest then used in the Kubernetes video.
Now, that was great,
but the astute observer might have realized
that we skipped a little step there.
Instead of submitting code to a CI system,
I just ran the build from my laptop
and then uploaded that directly.
That's a big no-no
if you work on a team with more than one person.
What we want is a pipeline
that builds our infrastructure
instead of engineers doing this on their laptops.
So, let's build a Docker container
and then deploy it
to the container registry that we're using, Docker Hub.
So for this video,
we're going to be using GitHub Actions.
And I'm at the documentation site
for GitHub Actions right now.
GitHub Actions are really great
because we can do all sorts of things,
from publishing a container to a registry,
like we'll do in this video,
or issuing an alert to Slack,
or even SSHing into a bastion box
and running Terraform commands.
Just take some time
to look through the GitHub marketplace
and see what you can mix and match together here.
We'll be using the build and push
Docker Images action.
Instead of creating our action in the command line,
I'm going to just do everything in the code editor
right in GitHub.
So, let's move over to my repo
and take a look at my workflow.
Right now, I'm in my action, build and publish,
but right now it doesn't really build and publish.
It just builds.
You can see we just have the build job here.
We need to make a new job for our action.
And since I'm chaining it to this one,
I'm going to add it below.
But first, I need a way to transfer my application binary
from this one job at the top here
to the new job that we're going to create.
I'm adding a bit of code here to upload an artifact.
Nothing too special here
other than I'm setting the name for my artifact.
Now I can reference it in my Docker build
and my push job as word-cloud-generator.
Okay, so now I'm going to do
a little bit of cooking show set up here
and paste in my job for build-docker.
All right, so now you can look at this next job
that I have here.
There's a keyword here up at the very top that says,
"Needs: build."
This tells the job that the build job before it must run,
and then it can run.
This is setting a dependency
inside of our workflow here.
This next section of code fetches our binary,
word-cloud-generator,
and then it sets up some Docker metadata,
like setting up our tags,
making sure we're able to lock
to whatever sha that we're using inside of GitHub.
And then you'll probably notice
that we're dealing with secrets here.
These are secrets that are inside of our GitHub Action,
and they let us log into Docker Hub.
Now, I had to do this out of band
as an admin on the repo,
so you'll have to do that separately
if you're following along on your own repo.
And then lastly,
we run the build and publish.
This puts it all together as our metadata
and uploads it up to Docker.
So, this is all good.
Let's go ahead and save this.
I'm going to run a commit.
I'm going to say,
"Adding publish for the container."
I'm going to go ahead and commit changes here.
Okay, now we can see that's running.
Let's go over to our actions.
And we can see that we're adding publish for the container.
Now, we see that we have two jobs,
build and then build-docker.
Let's see if we can update here to get our status.
And we see the build is starting to run.
So, we're going to speed all this up
with a little bit of movie magic here.
Okay, so we can see output from each stage.
So, build and then build-docker.
I really am very creative at naming these things.
Maybe I need to try a little harder here.
Okay, so let's move over to Docker Hub,
and we can now see our images that we just pushed up here.
So just a few seconds ago,
we have our latest tag
and then we have it with the sha as well.
So, that's it.
Now we have our container here
getting built, tested, deployed to our registry.
But before we call it a day,
let's go back and make a change to our container.
Let's say we want to make an OS version change.
So, I'm going back into word-cloud-generator,
and I'm going into my Docker file.
And so instead of using alpine:3.16,
let's bump the version to 3.17.
And I'm going to say,
update Docker file,
"Bumping to alpine:3.17."
So, we're just making an OS version change.
I'm going to commit changes there.
So, now we should have a new GitHub Action
that's taking that in.
And again, we'll use a little bit movie magic here.
Okay, so that's it.
We changed OS versions in our container
and we're able to build and deploy that as well.
The great thing about actions
is that we can now stack actions together
to trigger our environment to update
and use the new container,
as well as alert our team
that a new version has been published.
You know, CI is not just for applications anymore,
but it's a key part to infrastructure as code.