- [Narrator] Now it's time to look at Docker.
As we've talked about, Docker containers can be thought of
as Micro VMs and they package all the software
and application needs to run and nothing else,
or at least that's the promise of it.
Well, let's start with a look at Docker Desktop.
Notice on the left hand side,
we have containers, images, and volumes.
I'm clicking into images first and we don't have any images
available at the moment.
We need an image to be able to run a container
from that image.
So let's leave the desktop view and head on over
to the command line and make our image.
Now I'm in the Word-cloud generator GitHub repository
which is a GitHub repo
and features a Go Lang web application
I wrote for the LinkedIn Learning classes.
It takes text and turns it into,
you guessed it, a word-cloud.
In a few minutes,
we'll take a look at that, but for this video,
we're putting word-cloud generator into a docker container
and then when the container gets run,
it will execute the application.
Before we build our image,
let's look at how a Docker container gets built.
I'm opening up the project's MakeFile in Vim.
I'm typing Vim MakeFile.
There's an entry named Docker-Build.
In it, it has Build, Docker-build-Mac, and Docker-build-amd.
The one system dependency you have to remember
is the underlying architecture of the box,
like Intel or ARM and so on.
I'm building on an M2 Mac
which uses an ARM 64 architecture
but most servers are Intel or AMD based, which is AMD 64.
So we can use this Docker container
in Earnest Kubernetes cluster.
In the next video, we'll use the Buildx Cross Architecture
build tool to build it for AMD64 as well.
So let's get back to the build, it first runs build
before doing any Docker steps.
It runs for Linux, Windows, and Mac.
Once we have our artifact for the word-cloud generator app,
now we have to put it inside of a container.
For this, we'll be using Docker-build-Mac.
Docker-Build tells it which Docker file to look for.
It gives it a few tags
and then it looks in the local directory.
So let's open up
that Docker file and understand what it's doing.
I'm typing vim Dockerfile.
It starts with an Alpine Linux container,
which is a very lightweight Docker container,
which is roughly five megabytes in size.
That's awesome for us.
Next, it copies in our application artifact,
the word-cloud generator app
and it puts it in the op directory.
Next, it exposes a port
and then it has this command here entry point.
The entry point command specifies what is run
after the container is initiated.
This format is pretty standard
for a containerized application with a single purpose.
Okay, so let's just build it and I'm going to run
make Docker-Build.
Okay, that built my app
and made a new Docker image and put it inside of it.
Let's go back to Docker Desktop
and we can see our images that were created.
Notice there's only 12 megabytes in size.
Okay, so that's everything we need.
It's got the OS, the app.
That's everything we need to run in that small container.
It's pretty cool and it's very lightweight.
Now, I could run it right from the desktop
but let's go back to the command line again.
In my make file, I have Make-Docker-Run.
I'm going to call that right now.
Okay, so notice what it did here.
It started Docker and it put it on port 8888
and it mapped that port externally for that.
We can go see that in Docker Desktop again.
Okay, look, there's our container.
We can see it running.
It's running on port 8888.
Let's check it out.
Okay, we're on local hosts, port 8888
and I'm going to go ahead and paste in a few hundred words
from the Lorem Ipsum text generator
and let Word-cloud generator just do its thing.
Okay, great, it's all working.
Now we have our application.
It's in a container, it's running locally,
everything's good, but we want to share our image
with other people.
So let's go back to the command line and let's do just that.
I have another entry in my make file called Docker Push.
That puts the image that we made into Docker Hub,
which is a public docker registry that people can use
to share images.
As we mentioned earlier, we'll push both the Mac
and the Intel based images so we can use them
in multiple architectures.
So I'm going to type in make Docker-push.
Okay, great, got all the Docker containers pushed up there.
Let's go take a look at Docker Hub.
So I'm on Docker Hub and I can see all the containers
that just got pushed up.
And this is the admin interface since I own it
and we can see what it looks like to the public.
And here are the containers that would look like
for someone that wanted to download it.
So let's recap.
We have our web application bundled in a very small
Linux container that is invoked on startup and runs.
We then told Docker to run that image
and bind it to a high port
and then we ran against it and saw it in the browser,
but it's ephemeral and we could have just run a script
or a task and then asked it to exit.
Well, we forced it to stick around
and wait until we were done with it
because we're using it as a web application.
Then we shared our container with the world on Docker Hub.
Okay, that's a quick tour of what you can do with Docker.