- [Instructor] Now let's talk Serverless.
We don't have to mess
with setting up all the infrastructure in boxes,
and we can just get our code up and running.
For this, let's use the Serverless Framework,
which is free to use for open-source projects,
but it does have a subscription model for organizations.
Your provider might also offer one as well.
So like for AWS, check out the Serverless Application Model,
or AWS SAM.
So I've logged into my account on Serverless,
and I'm going to create a new application.
I'm just clicking Create App.
Now, there's a lot to choose from here,
from taking an existing application
into the Serverless Framework
or starting a sample application from scratch.
I'm selecting to create a Node Express API application.
But as you can see, there are a lot of options
for setting up the data stack as well.
All the components you need to run your application
can be configured with the framework
much like Ernest showed with Terraform.
Now let's give our Serverless app a name.
I'm going to type in "infra-as-code-demo"
and I'm going to go ahead and click Create,
and that gives us a command that we need to run.
So I'm going to take this and head on over to the command line
and I'm going to run that command.
Notice it's getting everything set up
and then it says, "Do you want to deploy now?"
Let's go ahead and do that.
Now it starts building out the cloud formation stack
so it can set up all the services
that it needs to connect to.
Once it's all done at the end, it's going to give us a URL.
Let's go test it out.
So in my browser, I just sent an HTTP GET request
and this is what I get back.
"Hello from root!" So kind of a default message here.
Let's head back to the command line
and look at the code for the application.
So I'm moving into the infra-as-code-demo
and we can see the serverless.yml.
Let's take a look at that.
In here, we can see that the handler that gets called
is the index.handler.
And let's go ahead and open up the the index here.
So I'm inside of the index.js
and we can see the response that we just saw in the browser.
It says "Hello from root!"
Let's move over to AWS.
I've logged into the admin console
and now we have an application
in the AWS Lambda Section here
that says "infra-as-code-demo-dev-api."
Once I click into it, I can see that I have my API Gateway,
which is the thing that receives the HTTP traffic,
and then it's sending it over
to my infra-as-code-demo Lambda function.
That's the really cool thing
about using the Serverless Framework.
It sets up the gateway and it connects it automatically
using the CloudFormation templates.
Pretty cool, right?
In here, we can monitor our function.
We can see different metrics
for how things are going with our Lambdas.
We can look at log events
and we can see our recent request that we just made.
And remember, Serverless is billed in time that it's in use.
This is usage-based billing.
That's great because you're only paying
for that execution time.
And if you have an infrequently used application,
you aren't paying to keep a box up and running
or multiple boxes up and running all the time.
Okay, now I'm going to switch back to the command line
and let's change what our app does
and give it a new message for that HTTP GET.
So I'm just going to say, "hi LinkedIn Learning!"
And we're going to write that.
And now we're just going to say "serverless deploy."
And we use a little video magic there to speed that up.
And now let's go back to our URL.
And now we get our message "Hi LinkedIn Learning!"
So to recap, we use the Serverless Framework,
which configured and deployed a Lambda and an API Gateway.
There are templates for much more, as you saw.
We had a running app in just a few lines of code
and it had ability to scale horizontally to handle hundreds,
if not a thousand requests at the same time.
Big bursts of traffic can be handled this way.
And we did all this without creating virtual machines
or Kubernetes pods or any infrastructure.
We tapped into our provider's services
and we get usage-based billing on top.
This means you have fewer things to maintain,
fewer things to have security vulnerabilities,
and, at medium to low volume, you usually have lower costs.
So I hope you enjoyed this quick look into Serverless.