- The cloud is great because you can get
the infrastructure you need
pretty much immediately when you need it.
- Okay, you're starting to sound like a commercial.
Do you work for Amazon now?
- [Announcer] Bare metal versus cloud, fight.
- You can't beat the cloud's agility.
Instead of waiting to buy hardware,
get it put into a data center,
and whatever annoying process your IT department ladles
on top of that,
you can get the servers you need with a click of a button,
bit of typing at a command line or a brief lick
of an API or whatever it is you do to an API.
- Okay, first of all, that's oddly disturbing.
Second of all, those servers aren't cheap Ernest
you can buy a good Dell server for what, about $5,000
but a cloud server of the same spec can cost you
like a $1.50 an hour.
Okay, when you put all that together
by my calculations, that's $13,000 in a year.
- For sure, one to one, the cloud can be more expensive,
but first of all if you're really running that server
all the time, you can get a savings plan
that'll cut 30% off the top.
You're also saving on administration and facility costs.
You're not just not buying that server
you're paying for the data center,
power, cooling, networking,
and system admins needed to make it work.
But maybe most importantly
cloud savings isn't about running servers one to one.
It's about right sizing your servers and fleet dynamically.
Think of a data center as a shipping container
full of liter containers of water.
The water's the work you're getting done
but many of the containers aren't full
and you're paying for the containers you have
and no matter how much water's in them.
In the cloud, it's like you can resize
the shipping container and the liter containers
to match the workload
and then you can save on all the excess.
- Are you done?
I mean, that's nice to put in the old cloud, to rain,
to drinking water analogy, but come on
since it's easy to just click and get more servers
aren't my employees just going to run rampant and you know
get a bunch of servers like there's no tomorrow
without a certified system administrator
or someone you know, watching and enforcing, you know
through compliance and audit?
- Well, sure, that can happen.
With great power comes great responsibility
as my Uncle Ben once said.
But it's easy to put governance
and quotas in place, and instead of having one big
organization be the giant cost center,
you can delegate out budget
to the orgs using it, which improves behavior
around cost and benefit organizationally.
- Okay, but isn't the cloud really complicated?
I mean, you hear comedians all the time saying things like
no one understands the cloud,
and it's all this newfangled and scary thing.
- Remember, we're comparing this to on-premise system
and network administration.
Pretty sure those standup comedians would be even
more puzzled by InfiniBand networking.
- Okay, okay, that's fair.
- While it is new, and those of us like me
who came from a traditional system admin background
needed to learn some new things in order to use the cloud
it's not any more complicated than an on-prem data center.
And frankly, since it's more standard
you don't get the weird old special snowflakes boxes
in the corner with a do not touch sign on them.
- Okay, but what if we need specialized hardware?
You can't get that in the cloud.
- Well, you'd be surprised, they have GPUs
FPGAs, quantum computing, 5G edge compute
and a lot of very diverse hardware in the cloud.
But yeah, if you have a lot of super custom hardware needs
you'll still need to roll your own.
Or if the cost instability
of your use case really means it's financially
appropriate to build out your own hardware,
but even then you probably want to use cloud for
all your other use cases that don't fit that description.
And in my experience, less than 10% do.
- Okay, Ernest, I'm convinced.
Like the kids say today, I'm down to cloud.
- Never say that again.
- No?
How about make it rain servers?
- That's another entry on the do not say list.
- Okay, well, that was our completely objective debate
on using real hardware versus using the cloud.
We hope you enjoyed it and learned from it.