- The cloud means different things to different people
but most expect network, compute, and storage.
Now at the dawn of cloud, that was enough
but today the cloud is way more.
Let's take a look at Azure's cloud offerings.
As you can see, the choices are numerous.
Besides the basic services
there's a long list of managed services.
You can get managed databases of any flavor
from managed MySQL databases, to map reduce, to DNS,
and CDNs, but it doesn't stop there.
The options also include observability
and security offerings.
And this isn't limited to Microsoft.
Every major cloud provider, AWS, GCP, OCI,
they all have a huge set of managed services
that go beyond simple infrastructure.
The goal here is to provide specific functionality
in a service that doesn't require the user to
configure the lower level servers and other components
in order to get their desire workload performed.
Here's a list of past services that Microsoft Azure
recommends you use instead of building
and configuring them manually,
as you would in an on-premise data center.
And they can be used to form sophisticated systems
all by themselves.
So here's a Microsoft example architecture
for a social media analytics solution.
It's completely composed of managed services.
Azure Synapse Analytics is used to ingest the data
and place it into Apache Spark pools.
It enriches that data using
Azure Cognitive Services Translator to translate text
and Azure Maps to link data to geographical coordinates.
It stores the data in a serverless SQL pool
inside Azure Synapse Analytics, and then makes it available
to users via Power BI dashboards.
While this solution certainly uses servers and databases
under the hood, you aren't interacting with them directly.
You're only interacting with the managed services
at a more functional level.
Store the data, translate this string,
geolocate this address, visualize the data,
that's what managed services are.
Next, we'll examine why you should always use them
and never use infrastructure ever again.