- I don't get the big deal about containers.
They're just slightly lighter Vms, right?
The cloud already lets us
spin up all the VMs we want dynamically.
- Well, actually, that's true, but--
- [Speaker] VMs versus containers, fight.
- Do you mind?
Anyway, that's true.
But servers, even cloud Vms, only come in fixed sizes,
and are slow to build and provision.
Containers build and run much more quickly,
and use less overhead when they do.
- Right, but that doesn't sound like that big of a deal.
I only build my servers once, and then they're done.
Who cares if it takes 10 minutes or one minute?
- That's what I thought
when I first had Docker explained to me, too.
The operational benefits are there,
but they're not super compelling
when compared one to one with a VM.
But it's not about one to one.
Like with moving to cloud from data centers,
it's the ability to use greater ephemerality
that really makes the difference.
- Okay, now hold on there, Mr. Big Words.
I'm from Texas.
What do you mean, ephemerality?
- Well, the old model
is that you carefully construct servers
in order to run a bunch of applications on them.
And then you have a whole world of hurt
from conflicting configurations,
maintenance schedules, and so on.
Containers separate that out,
so each application has just the environment it needs.
So you avoid version conflicts with things
like Java, Python run times, and other dependencies.
- Okay, but if you have a thousand containers
instead of a hundred servers,
isn't that just 10 times the maintenance burden?
- No, because container architectures
pressure you to run them for a short time,
like one piece of a workload, and then kill them.
They're intended to be read only,
no updates or SSHing into them or anything.
You can think of them as much as thick processes
than thin servers.
In the DevOps world, we often refer to the move
to standardized servers as cattle, not pets.
Using that same analogy,
you can think of a container as a specific packaged steak.
Hmm, steak.
- Hmm, okay, steak.
Now, now, now you're talking Texan.
So what you're saying is there's less
of an opportunity to drift,
but you still need to update them
for security patches and all that stuff, right?
- Sure, but because the beauty of Docker
is that each container is intended to be one service,
one or a very small number of processes.
With a minimal system environment customized to itself,
they're often not running an entire
traditional operating system in the container.
- Okay, so there's less surface area.
- Right, and since they build quickly,
Docker-based build pipelines
integrate the base container build
with the application build in the same pipeline.
Individual container images are immutable,
and not intended to be changed,
just new versions built
whenever you need a patch system or application.
- Okay, but doesn't that expose the sanctity
of my operating system configuration
to the, I hate to say it, developers?
I mean, my inner sys admin says that's a bad thing.
- Yes, but it's really a good thing.
Traditional system administration
relied on one set of people
carefully configuring the systems,
and another the applications.
'Cause one day, somebody heard the phrase,
separation of duties, skipped reading the definition,
and decided that was the way to do it.
- Oh, snap.
- But the real power of containers
is that they greatly accelerate
the feedback loop for developers.
Developers can run the identical container
easily on their desktop, on test systems,
and on production systems.
This finds integration problems early,
and speeds up the whole development cycle.
- Okay, of course, separation of duties
doesn't mean one person does systems,
and another does apps.
But it does mean that no single person
should have full control over something that's important.
And so doesn't this violate that?
- Well, the great thing
about container-based development workflows,
spoiler alert for later in the course,
is they can leverage the safeguards
of a well-designed build pipeline.
That means peer reviews to ensure separation of duties,
as well as automated testing,
functional security and so on, in a single integrated,
not siloed way.
- Okay, that sounds good.
But what if I said there was something
even better than containers For that?
You'll have to join me in my next video
to find out what it is.