- Let's move one layer past containers to serverless.
Serverless computing is something you may have heard about
but haven't tried out.
In this session,
we're going to demystify the term serverless
and dive into how it works.
The term serverless,
it doesn't mean that there's not a server
in there somewhere.
It just means that you don't have to interact
with it yourself.
Some managed services bill themselves as serverless
once they get to the level where you don't need
to configure system parameters or stuff like that yourself.
Some cloud databases and data pipeline services
are frequently billed as serverless, but the real heart
of serverless computing is functions as a service or FaaS.
Some examples of public cloud FaaS offerings
are Amazon Lambda, Google Cloud Functions,
and Azure Functions.
There are also open-source serverless platforms
that you have to install
and do some of the server part yourself
like Apache OpenWhisk, OpenFaaS, and Knative.
These usually work on top of Kubernetes
or other container platforms.
Well, let's explain this with an example architecture.
On the left is a traditional web application architecture.
A client talks literally to the web stack,
and the web servers are running
any number of services on them.
On the right is a serverless architecture.
You decompose the services into functions
with no central web server to speak of
as all of its roles and duties are now distributed.
Under the hood,
these functions are containers that get spun up
in milliseconds on a read-only file system
when they're requested.
They execute the event that is given to them,
and then they just disappear.
So you don't have persistently running servers,
you just have zero to many running invocations
of your function.
I find it helps to think about serverless like this.
Serverless encourages functions
as deploy units coupled with third-party services
that allow running end-to-end applications
without worrying about any of the system operation.
Since the functions are backed by come-and-go containers,
this begs the question of how do serverless functions
get instantiated or triggered?
And that's a good question.
You know, when serverless first came out,
it was often just being used to do event handling.
So you would upload a file, for example,
and that would trigger a function to process it.
So early Lambdas often did simple operations
like compressing a file or converting a file format.
But it wasn't too long before all that changed due
to the fact that these functions were ready in milliseconds
and the fact that HTTP traffic is just a series
of small events,
the industry started creating web applications
using a serverless architecture.
So here's an example of a serverless application composed
of serverless functions in AWS.
It's based on a real insurance underwriting application
that Ernest worked on that was completely serverless.
Web requests fired from a front end react application,
and they came in through an API gateway
to trigger specific functions like log in,
generating new contract, viewing existing contracts
and so on.
Individual dedicated chunks of code, perform operations
like saving information, generating a price quote,
creating a pdf, and emailing the potential client.
It breaks down every API into a set of serverless functions
and calls out to external services
like an accounting system and a database.
In this way, you can build large complex systems
without having to build or manage servers.
That sounds too good to be true, doesn't it?
Well, in the next video we'll talk about that.