- I've seen the future, and it doesn't have servers.
- I declare shenanigans!
Serverless still has servers
under the hood. - Okay, okay, professor.
- [Speaker] Serverless versus servers fight.
- Okay, let's jump into it.
Let's start by discussing the benefits of serverless.
- Okay, fair enough.
But where did you get that ridiculous hat?
- Oh, yeah, this, this old thing?
You like it?
- No.
- Serverless has three key benefits.
First, scaling is handled by the provider.
Second, it's pay for play.
If your app isn't running, it isn't costing you anything.
Third, you're no longer dealing with package management
or OS updates.
It's really a beautiful thing.
- Okay, that's all true,
but you're ignoring some of the downsides of serverless.
I'll match you three for three.
Each cloud vendor's platform works a little differently,
but I'm not even going to count that as a downside.
The big story is that each of them
has the same three fundamental limitations
that make some workloads just not suitable for serverless.
First, big apps have long initial cold start times,
which cause delays when calling infrequently used services.
Second, functions have a runtime limit
set by the cloud provider, like 15 minutes for AWS Lambda.
So long running jobs don't work.
And there's also some not well advertised limits
like the number of parallel Lambda executions you can have
in an AWS account.
And then third, serverless invocations
are relatively pretty expensive.
If you're running a lot of executions,
it can turn out to cost a lot more
than running a dedicated service yourself.
- Well, I think you're at least partially right
about the cost.
Unless you're running your own serverless platform
like K Native on top of Kubernetes,
but then you're doing all the work to running yourself.
So, you know.
- Okay, so it's settled.
- Well, not so fast there, Ernest.
I'll give you that.
But your other points about restrictions and limitations
are just facts of computing.
Not every workload fits on every platform,
but there's often ways to get more mileage
out of serverless in these cases.
You know, very large apps
may not be best for serverless web services,
but caching and asynchronous responses
can often improve cold start experiences.
Long running apps may be decomposed into steps,
using step functions,
and apps that have many concurrent executions
may not be the best cost model,
but it takes you quite a while to get there.
So you can defer the cost of a more complex solution
til the time comes that you really need it.
- Okay, well, since you seem so sure
of handling the downsides of serverless,
why don't you tell us more about why it's so great?
- Yeah, sure.
Well, let's start with how people are using it.
In fact, in the last video,
I showed how you had built out an entire application
through linking a series of serverless functions
and cloud services, and that was pretty cool.
- Thanks.
I mean, that must be some other Earnest.
- There's only room for one Earnest in my life.
I often advise that before people
undertake a full serverless approach,
they could transition just one part of their application
or stack to serverless by looking for places
where they're handling events or processing queues
or using admin scripts, creating an API,
or maybe even using HTTP traffic
like single page web applications.
- That makes sense.
I learned that you can do a lot with serverless.
Oh wait, whose side am I on?
That's right, don't take my server.
- Okay, Ernest, here is something for you to consider.
When you have a server,
whether it be a cloud VM or actual real hardware,
or even a Kubernetes pod or node,
what is it doing most of the time?
- Well, most of the time,
it's running my application, well,
and a bunch of other stuff.
- Bingo.
One of the best reasons to use serverless
is that you have more direct visibility
of what resources your app actually uses,
not mixed in with a bunch of other plumbing.
And an underappreciated aspect to this
is that for the first time in our industry,
performance improvements and enhancements,
they can be directly tied to cost,
without having to use an interpretive model.
With you being a longtime web performance expert,
I think you'd have to love that.
- Well, he got me with that one.
Where's my hat?
- You know, it looks really good on you.
- Join us in the next section,
where we discuss how to take all this infrastructure
we've been talking about and codify it.