- Before we talk about the code part
of infrastructure as code,
we want to start out with this chapter
talking about modern infrastructure
and how it lends itself to automation.
In this video, we're going to talk about
one of my favorite subjects, cloud computing.
If you're familiar with using the cloud,
this may just be a refresher for you,
but we wanted to do some explanation
for folks that haven't gotten to work with the cloud yet
and may have only heard about it.
So what is the cloud,
besides the place your photos go to die?
While arguing about what is cloud
was popular for a few years,
most agree that the definition
that the US National Institute of Standards and Technology
put out in 2011 is sufficiently definitive.
Cloud is characterized by on demand,
self-service provisioning, broad network access,
resource pooling, rapid elasticity, and measured service.
And there are three general cloud service models.
Software as a service, or SaaS,
is where an entire application is provided for you
live from the internet.
Salesforce, TurboTax, and Office 365 are examples of SaaS.
Platform as a service, or PaaS,
is where you can deploy custom applications
to the cloud platform without managing
the underlying systems yourself.
Google App Engine, Microsoft Azure App Service,
and Pivotal Web Services or examples of public PaaSes.
Infrastructure as a service,
pronounced I-A-A-S for obvious reasons,
is where you get operating system level access
to discrete systems in the cloud.
These are usually VMs and not bare metal.
Google Compute Engine, Microsoft Azure Virtual Machines,
and Amazon Web Services EC2 showcase IaaS offerings.
Of course, in the last decade plus
cloud offerings have gotten more sophisticated
and are part of practically everything.
Your Nest home thermostat, cell phone, Alexa,
and so on all use cloud services.
But this mysterious force that rules your life
is really just servers in real world data centers.
Cloud providers like Amazon Web Services
make servers, storage, and more available to use at a click.
You can go sign up for an AWS account using their free tier
or with a credit card,
go into their EC2 Elastic Compute service,
click to choose the size of the server you want,
what operating system you want.
In about five minutes,
you can have a Windows or Linux server
of just about any size with as much storage as you want,
even with GPUs and other high performance add-ons.
You can open it up to the whole internet
to host a web server on,
or keep it locked down for just your use.
But you can reach it from anywhere in the world
that you can jack into cyberspace,
as the kids say nowadays,
The cloud providers can do this,
because they have big data centers
full of servers and storage around the world
and they're just assigning one of them to you
when you ask for it.
That's a big difference from the old days
of fighting with a system admin team for six weeks
to get three more servers into the data center.
Anyway, this means if you need two
or a hundred servers instead of just one,
you can easily ask for that many
and scale right up in minutes.
Amazon can rent that capacity out
to somebody else when you're not using it,
so they just charge you by the minute.
Like we used to pay per minute
for long distance phone calls.
If you need to just use a computer for four hours,
you pay for four hours.
You're not buying a physical server
that you have to pay full price for upfront
and then keep around whether you're using it or not
or whether it breaks or not.
And that's the cloud in a nutshell.
Instead of buying your own hardware,
waiting for it to get put into a data center and loaded up,
and then depreciating it over time
while you get sadder and sadder
about its performance every year,
you could just reach out, grab a resource
of the size you want, get it right now,
just pay for it while you use it.
And maybe most importantly, to use the cloud,
sure, you can use their UI or command line tools,
but all the clouds have a fully featured API
that you can integrate with your own tools or code.
In our next video,
we'll talk about when you might use the cloud
and when you might want to use your own data center.