- Managed services are great
because we don't have to do all the care
and feeding of infrastructure
and can focus on delivering value.
- Okay now you're starting to sound like a commercial.
Do you work for Amazon now?
- [Narrator] Managed services versus Bare Cloud fight.
- But managed services get you so much more
than basic services do,
you know, for example
let's say you want to try out a new database.
Previously you would've hired consultants
to get it up and running or found expert staff
but neither of them are cheap.
- Yeah but is that database really fully managed?
You still need database expertise
for your schema and your tuning,
even though you may not have to manage the servers
the database is still largely up to you to configure.
- Okay yeah, you still have some things to do
but not nearly as many.
Instead, you can now make a few API calls
and have a full database ready to go
managed by your provider and ready to scale instead
of waiting for a month or two
for your DBAs to get around to doing something.
- But that abstraction layer is preventing you from tuning
and doing like the deep down details you need to do
for super demanding workloads, isn't it?
- Okay, sure,
if you're one of the FAANG companies,
you can worry about that, but 90% of the companies out there
they don't really need that level of customization
and no one really needs it
for the majority of their services, just the key ones.
Okay so in the case of Kubernetes
would you rather run your own cluster
and manage it and all the ins and outs of Kubernetes
or would you rather use EKS from Amazon
and get all the benefits
without having to hire all the new staff Ernest?
- It's great if you want to use
what the man wants you to use,
what if they don't have the version
or functionality or whatever you need?
For example, the managed Kubernetes services
are always lagging behind the newest releases
and so you miss out on a lot of the cutting edge features
and you can't customize as much
as you can when you're running it directly.
- Okay yeah, sure, yeah you may be a bit behind
the bleeding edge of a particular technology,
but that may be seen as a positive in many organizations,
for small teams or the scrappy startup
looking to build out services
the friction and cost has really been significantly reduced.
- But from the startup point of view
they're also more expensive.
You pay for all that management
they put on top of it.
In one shop I used MongoDB Atlas,
their managed database service,
and it was cool that I could upgrade versions
or server sizes with the click of a button,
but then they charged me out the nose for backups.
- Okay, definitely,
but what could your engineering effort
that you save do to accelerate the actual startup,
you know and the success of it,
and it's often worth money
to get back all that engineering time.
Managed services aren't just for startups either.
Many of the companies that we've both worked at
in the last decade, including mid-size enterprises
have migrated completely
to public cloud hosting for their computing needs,
and this includes using more
than just compute and network and storage.
- Well, but that brings up
another challenge with managed services.
They're not portable across clouds or to your data center.
If you're using one cloud service
it's often not compatible at all with another's.
- Okay well but isn't that great from a buyer's perspective?
You know, competition between all the major cloud providers
and all the options we get to use,
we never thought we would've had those in the pre-cloud era.
- I mean, it is, except for the harm it often does
to those open source ecosystems.
The cloud providers have sometimes been fairly predatory
in taking open source products
and forking and monetizing them
to the detriment of those communities health.
- Okay all right, out of everything you've said,
you do have a point there,
but as for the rest of your points about customizability
and multi-cloud what percentage of the shops
that you've worked at in the last 20 years,
where they've really needed any of that,
instead of just moving more quickly to market?
- Well maybe 10%.
- Okay I rest my case.
(banging)