- Now I know what you're saying.
Cloud is so early-2000s.
Containers are all the buzz right now,
and they're a fundamental empowering technology
for infrastructure as code.
So what is a container, you may ask?
It's a lightweight, executable unit of software
that packs up a system environment, application code,
and dependencies such as binaries, libraries,
and configuration files for easy deployment
across different computing environments.
In other words, it's basically a way to run
segmented mini systems on your Linux or Windows host system.
I know, I know that sounds like a virtual machine,
but containers only virtualize down to the level
above the core operating system ,
while VMs virtualize all the way down to the hypervisor.
Because containers share the system's kernel,
they boot fast and are more lightweight
than a traditional virtual machine,
but they do provide isolation so you can install packages
and do system configuration restricted to the container.
In other words, they look like separate systems,
for most purposes, from inside them.
In fact, you don't need an operating system
in your container.
Since it uses the underlying POSIX OS of the server,
a container can just have, say,
a Golang or Python interpreter as its base layer
and be very slim.
Docker's the most popular container technology,
but there are others like CoreOS rkt,
containerd, and Red Hat CRI-O.
You create the container images that they use
in a code-like way.
Docker uses a build file called a Dockerfile.
Here is an example.
You just docker build this, and it starts by taking
the latest Ubuntu base container off Docker Hub,
which is a central Docker image repository
with community contributed images.
Then it downloads, installs, and runs
the NGINX web server on it
and opens up port 80 to the outside network.
The result is a Docker image you can run at will,
and every run of it generates a new container
running a web server.
You can then upload the image
to a container image repository
to be pulled down and used by developers
and by production systems.
The popular open source system, Kubernetes,
orchestrates containers en masse across multiple servers
to form a whole networked architecture
of many small services cooperating to form applications.
Here's an example: complex Kubernetes system
with relatively small pieces of code,
also called microservices,
running in a variety of containers and pods
across a set of nodes.
Kubernetes handles running the containers
and moving them around on nodes for resilience and scaling.
And it also handles the network connectivity
between services and from outside the system.
Because containers can be built quickly and easily
from description files and carry their own environment
along with them so that they can be run
in development and production environments identically,
they've become a popular base for application development,
and they lend themselves very well
to infrastructure as code.