- Alright, let's get down into the details a bit more
about what each box in our system is, how it gets created,
and how it stays up to date.
By box, we mean the individual running system,
whether it's hardware, a virtual machine,
a cloud instance, or a container.
First, we'll start
with defining a few key terms to help us think
about our boxes and our system,
and how they're configured to run both initially
and over time.
This process is generally known as configuration management.
Provisioning is the process of making a server or node ready
for operation, including installing the OS,
system services,
and establishing network connectivity.
Deployment is the process of deploying
and upgrading applications on a server.
Now, these two terms are mainly different
for historical reasons.
You know, like a developer, they might only think
about deploying an application and its APIs,
and an operations engineer is, you know, worried
about provisioning the OS and the network components.
But consider if you're using version code
for your infrastructure,
and version infrastructure for your applications,
you can use many of the same tools to roll out both.
Configuration management tools like Chef
and Puppet can make both operating system-level changes
and deploy applications using the same semantics.
You can even drive both
of them out of the same build system.
Here's an example
of a chef recipe to install a standard OS package
for the Apache 2 web server.
It's smart enough to understand which package to use
on RPM-based systems and which to use on Yum-based systems.
You just have Chef run on a node and it'll check to see
if the package exists and, if not, it'll install it.
And then here's a Chef recipe to install an application.
In this case, the golang cloud generator
that we wrote.
It downloads a zip file from the application
from our Nexus artifact repository, unzips it,
and runs it.
In this way, you can use code to do all the OS, network,
and security, application configuration,
everything that you need
for a base operating system to get all the way
to a fully configured and working server
without all the manual steps.
Infrastructure and services need to be managed
after their initial creation, of course.
Initial provisioning and deployment is great,
but being able to control and upgrade a running system,
that's also critical.
This includes detecting whether the system is really working
in the state you desired, or if it's broken
from a manual change, a runtime error or something
in the cloud provider, and you want to be able to roll
out new versions and changes the same way you initially
provisioned your system.
This brings us to another important concept: orchestration.
Orchestration is the act of performing
coordinated operations across multiple systems.
Once a system is running, it can be disruptive
to update it while it's in use.
An orchestration system keeps a registry
of the systems you're running
and allows you to coordinate deployments.
For example,
by draining web connections and then taking a server out
of a load balancer while you upgrade its application version
and then putting it back into service,
then you can repeat the process with the other servers.
The point is that the orchestration system needs
to give you ability to roll out changes of any type
while minimizing downtime and customer disruption.
Tools like Ansible
and Rundeck let you construct workflows to operate
on your system in an orchestrated manner.
And newer tools like Kubernetes promote different models
of orchestrated deployments with containers.
Now these are the building blocks
of configuration management using infrastructure as code.
But you may already be wondering how exactly to use them.
You know, which tools to use, when to use them,
and if you should think of your system
as long-running boxes where changes are applied in place
or replace the boxes for each deployment.
Now, this is a great question,
and there are reasons why you would choose one approach
over the other, and we'll cover
that in detail in the next two videos.