- I declare that the system should exist.
- It doesn't work that way.
- Ah, but I declared it!
- It's imperative we stopped messing around.
- Ah, I see what you did there.
- [Announcer] Declarative versus Imperative, fight!
- There are two main options
for how a configuration management system works:
declarative and imperative.
In a declarative approach,
developers specify the desired state
and let configuration management
determine how best to achieve it.
"Chef" and "Puppet" are declarative tools.
You say, I want this package installed
and the recipes are written in a way
where they'll check if the system is already configured,
and, if not, it'll change it.
And it'll keep on running to try to get it that way
if it doesn't take the first time.
That's called being convergent.
As, over time, the tool works on converging the system
to the desired state.
The developer is less concerned with how it actually happens
and usually has only to be concerned
with the desired state at the end.
- Okay, so let's compare that with the imperative model.
In the imperative approach,
developers specify the order of actions to be taken
to achieve the desired result.
The imperative tools are more expressive
and allow the developer to perform complex,
conditional logic in the system.
Think of this as something like Ansible,
Salt, Rundeck or even Shell script.
They're a lot more explicit about the resources they manage
and they give the developer full control
over how the system changes are applied.
- [Instructor 1] The declarative model specifies
the desired in-state of the system;
it specifies the "what" we want to happen.
- [Ernest] Whereas the imperative model specifies
"how" the end-state is achieved.
- The declarative model is easier,
because it allows configuration management
to deal with all the details.
- You lie, I like having control.
- No, no, no.
Hear me out, Ernest.
Declarative tools are simpler and less error prone.
Things like Shell scripts don't really do a good job
of checking to see if they needed
to make a change in the first place,
or testing to see if they made the change successfully.
- Well, that's the theory.
Declarative tools arose in the early days of DevOps
to make configuration management
less bespoke and more standard.
And they work well in desktop or lab environments
where you don't really need control,
you just want all the boxes
to upgrade themselves at some point.
But how we use systems has changed
and it makes declarative tools less
suitable, now.
- What does that mean?
- I'd say most of the large scale systems
I've worked on in the last 10 years
have been running applications
that need more careful orchestration
of their upgrades and changes.
Those declarative tools tend to have
a convergent model of employment
that says, "Well I'll try to upgrade
these a hundred servers at no particular time,
and if they fail, I'll just keep trying
to get them into the declarative state, no hurry."
If those applications are coordinated
with a database change or serving trafficked customers
that shouldn't be getting random old and new answers,
that's a problem.
You need the the control of an imperative system,
because they're easier to orchestrate.
- But if you do imperative provisioning,
you're assuming those systems will always stay
in your desired in-state.
You know, systems are complex and they change over time.
The actual state of the system
will diverge from what the developer knows to be true,
whether through the resource provider
or even the OS package level.
You just can't know everything in your system,
resulting in the developer's mental model about the system
not matching the actual system state.
- You're right, it leaves the problem
of drift detection to you.
- Okay, so you're on my side now.
- Well, maybe. The thing is, with the rise
of VMs and containers,
individual systems are less complex, now.
Instead of let's put a bunch of applications
on one server, like we used to.
- Ah, yes.
The good old days.
I remember our app server cluster well
with 30 Java applications on it.
- Yeah. I thought the pages would never end,
but anyway, we have much less complex individual systems.
Often we'll maybe add a couple packages
and then one app service, and then go.
With containers and serverless,
often there's not even a need for any OS provisioning.
For these, a simpler imperative approach
is way more understandable and testable.
- But what about your overall network?
It's so easy to lose track of things
if you're just making a single imperative change.
- True. The good thing about cloud infrastructure
is that it has a single standard A-P-I to use to control it.
And then it's more of a solved problem
to instantiate a declarative model.
For anything that has controlled APIs
for deployment, orchestration and runtime,
then yeah, it makes sense to go with a declarative approach.
However, if you're needing more control
inside the box or system, for OS level packages,
I find it better to think about that as an imperative model.
- Right on.
That makes sense to me as a good delineator,
for those thinking about which direction to go.
That's what I see people doing, too.
A declarative tool like Terraform
is the current favorite for infrastructure provisioning
and then for systems, an imperative tool like Ansible,
or even just a couple lines of Shell,
if it's a container, it seems to be the lead option there.
- It still seems like there could be
a better solution, though.
Running the same installs on a thousand servers
is just asking for some of them to break
and it seems wasteful.
What if we could just build the entire system
and then roll it out?
Then the the systems themselves could be immutable
and not need to change over time.
- Ah, the old tinfoil versus golden image debate is back.
- Did you say tinfoil hat?
- No, I wasn't saying tin foil hat, I was,
- Join us in the next video
to find out if immutable deployment is a better approach.