- Well, I know we just learned in the last video
that imperative provisioning is best.
- I think you mean declarative.
- But there's an even better approach.
Immutable provisioning.
Everything versus immutable, fight.
- What do you mean, immutable?
- Well, immutable deployments mean
that pieces of your infrastructure
aren't intended to be changed after deployment.
But instead are destroyed and recreated to affect changes.
- Well, that doesn't make any sense.
You have to change what's on your servers.
- Or do you?
- Yes.
- Well, but remember all our new infrastructure options.
You can throw away an old server
and create a new one in minutes.
At Netflix, for example, they popularized
an architecture where you bake new Amazon images
for every code change, and put whole squads
of them into service to conduct a rollout.
- Yeah, but isn't that kind of course grained,
replacing whole servers just to make
a code change, or a security patch?
- We've all had just a security patch brick systems.
This approach lets you build, test, and roll out
your infrastructure change in a reasoned way.
Truly identical to a code change.
It also lets you perform more sophisticated
rollout strategies, like blue green deployments
and canarying, with your infrastructure,
not just with your applications.
- I don't know, it seems like a lot of work
to do all that creation and destruction.
Isn't it kind of, you know, wasteful and risky?
- Most modern systems scale up and down
as part of normal operation anyway,
so it's largely the same mechanism
which adds to reliability.
And having a CM tool try to make
the same, complex software change
across a hundred servers is a lot more work.
And the chance that it'll go wrong
on one or more of them is, it's there.
If you do the install once, to immutable artifact
and deploy that, you're actually doing a lot less work.
- Okay, I seem to remember a classic
DevOps article by Luke Kanies,
called Golden Image or Foil Ball.
That showed how hard it was to manage images
and that you should use CM tools, though.
You don't want to cross Luke, do you?
- Not me.
But with respect, it was true at the time.
But that was 2009, and most imaging
was slow and not scalable.
I used Ghost to clone hard drives in the '90s too.
- Well, snap.
- But now tools like Packer let you stamp out
version VM images, and Docker lets you
stamp out version Docker images.
And the tools to manage them exist now.
Furthermore, like we've been talking about,
the move to microservices and modern scaling
tend to putting a limited load out on each given system,
so that they're very specific in their role.
If you can track the compiled artifacts of your code
you can track the compiled artifacts of your infrastructure.
- Okay, I see your point.
But, you can't just throw away your database, can you?
What about things that need to be persistent?
- True enough.
Although that just means you can't throw away your storage.
Plenty of people run redundant sets
of database servers that you can roll.
MongoDB is great for this.
Or database engines in a container,
that mount their storage on a separate drive.
- Okay, if your production environment
is really immutable, how do you log in
and make changes to fix production problems?
- You're right, it takes a different approach.
Plenty of observability, so that you can
figure out what's wrong, and then you fix
the code and deploy a new version.
So you tend to be tied to your deploy pipeline.
It needs to be really fast and reliable to make this work.
- But where does it stop though?
I mean, do you make your entire network
one big thing that you just throw away?
Or just the servers, or the containers on the servers?
Where does it all end, Ernest?
- That's a good question.
And it does depend on what you're doing.
If you try to deploy a very complex system,
you've gotten yourself back into the problem
that immutable building blocks has gotten you out of.
Netflix works at a giant scale, so they can just
swing in a whole new VPC full of mostly identical systems.
Most people don't immutably deploy things
like their base VPC network, but do use
baked system images and containers
and orchestrate from there.
Kubernetes is kind of the poster child for this.
You have a core node image and containers.
And then it handles deployment,
scale up and down, replacement, and so on.
- Okay, I see where you're coming from.
It's just such a big change from what we all
used to do in system administration.
- I feel you.
In the end, we're just moving up one level of abstraction.
In the old times, even single processes
weren't always immutable.
But we quickly learned that for 99% of use cases
you want processes that act just like each other.
And not to mess with them, expecting to spawn and kill them.
Now, changes to running processes
is generally just a tell of a security compromise.
- Right, you know I always used to compile
Apache myself on every server.
And when suddenly you could just install
a pre-compiled Apache from a package,
I wasn't sure what to think of it.
But it ended up saving me time
and let me worry about higher level abstractions.
- And to be fair, you still have
your same declarative or imperative choice.
It's just that action is taking place
in the build stage, and you're just running
the resulting immutable artifacts in production.
- Hornswaggled again, Ernest.
- And that's immutable deployment.
It's not the right thing for every case,
but it has compelling advantages in a lot.
I might dare say the majority of cases.
Now stay with us.
We're done talking smack and we're going to hit the code.
And show you how to use real tools
to implement all these concepts in our provisioning lab.